<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>High Availability on PIGSTY</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/</link><description>Recent content in High Availability on PIGSTY</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RPO Trade-offs</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/rpo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/rpo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPO&lt;/strong&gt; (Recovery Point Objective) defines the &lt;strong&gt;maximum amount of data loss&lt;/strong&gt; allowed when the primary fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For scenarios where data integrity is critical, such as financial transactions, RPO = 0 is typically required, meaning no data loss is allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, stricter RPO targets come at a cost: higher write latency, reduced system throughput, and the risk that replica failures may cause primary unavailability.
For typical scenarios, some data loss is acceptable (e.g., up to 1MB) in exchange for higher availability and performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>RTO Trade-offs</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/rto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/rto/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RTO&lt;/strong&gt; (Recovery Time Objective) defines the &lt;strong&gt;maximum time required for the system to restore write capability&lt;/strong&gt; when the primary fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For critical transaction systems where availability is paramount, the shortest possible RTO is typically required, such as under one minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, shorter RTO comes at a cost: increased false failover risk. Network jitter may be misinterpreted as a failure, leading to unnecessary failovers.
For cross-datacenter/cross-region deployments, RTO requirements are typically relaxed (e.g., 1-2 minutes) to reduce false failover risk.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Service Access</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/svc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha/svc/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Split read and write operations, route traffic correctly, and deliver PostgreSQL cluster capabilities reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#service-overview"&gt;Service&lt;/a&gt; is an abstraction: it represents the form in which database clusters expose their capabilities externally, encapsulating underlying cluster details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services are crucial for &lt;a href="#access-services"&gt;stable access&lt;/a&gt; in production environments, showing their value during automatic failover in &lt;a href="https://pigsty.io/docs/concept/ha"&gt;high availability&lt;/a&gt; clusters. &lt;a href="#personal-users"&gt;Personal users&lt;/a&gt; typically don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about this concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="personal-users"&gt;Personal Users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of &amp;ldquo;service&amp;rdquo; is for production environments. Personal users with single-node clusters can skip the complexity and directly use instance names or IP addresses to access the database.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>