<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business on PIGSTY</title><link>https://pigsty.io/tags/business/</link><description>Recent content in Business on PIGSTY</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 18:48:49 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pigsty.io/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/about/faq/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-is-pigsty-and-what-is-it-not"&gt;What is Pigsty, and what is it not?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pigsty is a PostgreSQL database distribution, a local-first open-source RDS cloud database solution.
Pigsty is not a Database Management System (DBMS), but rather a tool, distribution, solution, and best practice for managing DBMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analogy: The database is the car, then the DBA is the driver, RDS is the taxi service, and Pigsty is the autonomous driving software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id="what-problem-does-pigsty-solve"&gt;What problem does Pigsty solve?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ability to use databases well&lt;/strong&gt; is extremely scarce: either hire database experts at high cost to self-build (hire drivers), or rent RDS from cloud vendors at sky-high prices (hail a taxi), but now you have a new option: Pigsty (autonomous driving).
Pigsty helps users use databases well: allowing users to self-build higher-quality and more efficient local cloud database services at less than 1/10 the cost of RDS, without a DBA!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Isn't Cloud Computing More Profitable Than Sand Mining?</title><link>https://pigsty.io/blog/cloud/profit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/blog/cloud/profit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vonng.com/en/cloud/profit/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://pigsty.io/img/hero/cloud/profit.jpg" alt="featured"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public cloud margins worse than sand mining—why are pig-butchering schemes losing money? Resource-selling models heading toward price wars, open source alternatives breaking monopoly dreams! Service competitiveness gradually neutralized—where is the cloud computing industry heading? How did domestic cloud vendors make a business with 30-40% pure profit less profitable than sand mining? &lt;a href="https://vonng.com/en/cloud/profit/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>