<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PolarDB on PIGSTY</title><link>https://pigsty.io/tags/polardb/</link><description>Recent content in PolarDB on PIGSTY</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://pigsty.io/tags/polardb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PolarDB PG</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/pgsql/kernel/polardb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/pgsql/kernel/polardb/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pigsty allows you to create PostgreSQL clusters with &amp;ldquo;domestic innovation qualification&amp;rdquo; credentials using PolarDB!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PolarDB for PostgreSQL is essentially equivalent to PostgreSQL 15. Any client tool compatible with the PostgreSQL wire protocol can access PolarDB clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pigsty&amp;rsquo;s PGSQL repository provides PolarDB PG open-source installation packages for EL7 / EL8, but they are not downloaded to the local software repository during Pigsty installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need offline installation support for PolarDB PG, please consider our &lt;a href="https://pigsty.io/docs/about/service"&gt;professional subscription service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PolarDB Oracle</title><link>https://pigsty.io/docs/pgsql/kernel/polardb-o/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pigsty.io/docs/pgsql/kernel/polardb-o/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Pigsty allows you to create PolarDB for Oracle clusters with &amp;ldquo;domestic innovation qualification&amp;rdquo; credentials using PolarDB!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href="http://www.itsec.gov.cn/aqkkcp/cpgg/202312/t20231226_162074.html"&gt;Security and Reliability Evaluation Results Announcement (No. 1, 2023)&lt;/a&gt;, Appendix 3, Centralized Database. PolarDB v2.0 is an autonomous, controllable, secure, and reliable domestic innovation database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PolarDB for Oracle is an Oracle-compatible version developed based on PolarDB for PostgreSQL. Both share the same kernel, distinguished by the &lt;code&gt;--compatibility-mode&lt;/code&gt; parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collaborate with the Alibaba Cloud kernel team to provide a complete database solution based on PolarDB v2.0 kernel and Pigsty v3.0 RDS. Please contact sales for inquiries, or purchase on Alibaba Cloud Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>